export const questions = [
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following professions has the highest projected employment for 2024?",
    correctAnswer: "Financial Advisor",
    propositions: ["Teacher", "Economist", "Truck driver", "Financial Advisor"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is NOT a learning objective in this course?",
    correctAnswer: "How to make money",
    propositions: [
      "Applying psychology and sociology to finance",
      "How to make money",
      "Regulating financial markets",
      "How we incentivize people to get things done",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to Andrew Carnegie, what should somebody do once she is wealthy?",
    correctAnswer: "Retire early and commit to philanthropy while young",
    propositions: [
      "Throw extravagant parties to help her wealth trickle down",
      "Pass it on to her children",
      "Retire early and commit to philanthropy while young",
      "Retire late to accumulate as much wealth as possible, and then give the wealth away",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why is it relevant that finance tends to attract large amounts of money?",
    correctAnswer: "All of the above",
    propositions: [
      "Money can be used for good or evil",
      "Finance attracts people from around the globe",
      "Financial markets are a critical components of economic success",
      "All of the above",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "A stress test: (check all that apply)",
    correctAnswer:
      "Tries to incorporate all the interconnections between financial institutions.",
    propositions: [
      "Tries to incorporate all the interconnections between financial institutions.",
      "Aims to test the behavior of historical returns and their fluctuations during all sorts of potential financial crises.",
      "Tries to incorporate all potential economic and financial crises, such as recessions, appreciation and depreciation of currency, liquidity crisis, etc.",
      "Does not look at historical returns, and looks at all the details of the portfolios and their vulnerabilities during all sorts of potential financial crises.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "A 5% 3-month Value At Risk (VaR) of $1 million represents:",
    correctAnswer:
      "A 5% chance of the asset declining in value by $1 million during the 3-month time frame.",
    propositions: [
      "A 5% decline in the value of the asset after 3 month, per each $1 million of notional.",
      "A 5% chance of the asset increasing in value by $1 million during the 3-month time frame.",
      "A 5% chance of the asset declining in value by $1 million during the 3-month time frame.",
      "The likelihood of a 5% of $1 million decline in the asset over the next 3-month.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM), a measure of systematic risk is captured by:",
    correctAnswer: "The Beta.",
    propositions: [
      "The standard deviation of returns.",
      "The variance of returns.",
      "The Beta.",
      "The Alpha.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Market (or systematic) risk ___________ whereas idiosyncratic risk __________.",
    correctAnswer:
      "Is the risk for an asset to experience losses due to factors that affect the entire stock market; Is the risk which is endemic to a specific asset and therefore not the market as a whole",
    propositions: [
      "Is the risk for an asset to not be able to be traded in the market at a later time",
      "Is the risk for an asset to experience losses due to factors that affect the entire stock market; Is the risk which is endemic to a specific asset and therefore not the market as a whole",
      "Is the risk for an asset to experience losses due factors that solely affect the industry associated with the asset; Is the risk which is endemic to the industry of the asset and therefore not the market as a whole",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why might an investor not normally invest large sums of money into Walmart or Apple stock?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Their stock prices are highly volatile, and thus carry a lot of risk",
    propositions: [
      "Both companies have received extensive media coverage",
      "The stock prices are very stable, making it difficult to gain large sums of money",
      "Their stock prices are highly volatile, and thus carry a lot of risk",
      "Their stock prices closely track the S&P500",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why is the normal distribution not a good model of some financial data?",
    correctAnswer: "Extreme events occur in it too often",
    propositions: [
      "Extreme events occur in it too often",
      "The standard deviation is too high",
      "It does not have many outliers",
      "The standard deviation is too low",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these best describes risk pooling?",
    correctAnswer:
      "If individual events are independent, risk can be decreased by averaging across all of the events",
    propositions: [
      "If individual events are not independent, risk can be decreased by averaging across all of the events",
      "If individual events are independent, risk can be decreased by averaging across all of the events",
      "Insurance companies must avoid situations whereby customers are incentivized to intentionally cause an incident (e.g. burning their house down)",
      "Sick people are more likely to sign up for health insurance, and healthy people will not purchase the policy because this will make the premium more expensive",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following was NOT a factor which led to the proliferation of life insurance?",
    correctAnswer: "New sales pitches",
    propositions: [
      "Insurance salespeople",
      "Increased life expectancy",
      "Statistical data on life expectancy",
      "New sales pitches",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What happens in the United States if your insurance company goes bankrupt?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Consumers are insured from insurance company failure at the state level",
    propositions: [
      "There is no protection from the government against insurance company failure",
      "Consumers are insured from insurance company failure at the state level",
      "Insurance companies are partially owned by the government, and thus are not allowed to fail.",
      "Just like the FDIC protects consumers from bank failures, the federal government insures against insurance company failures",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What problem does the US Affordable Care Act (“Obamacare”) attempt to address and how does it do so?",
    correctAnswer:
      "It addresses selection bias by forcing everybody to buy health insurance or else face a tax penalty.",
    propositions: [
      "It addresses selection bias by forcing everybody to buy health insurance or else face a tax penalty.",
      "It addresses selection bias by creating a healthcare system which is fully publicly-funded.",
      "It addresses moral hazard by forcing hospitals to provide emergency services to those who cannot pay for it.",
      "It addresses moral hazard by allowing hospitals to refuse treatment to those who cannot pay for it.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of the main reasons why many homeowners did not have flood insurance before the advent of Hurricane Katrina in 2005 was:",
    correctAnswer:
      "Homeowners thought that the likelihood of a flood was too low to justify buying a flood insurance.",
    propositions: [
      "Many homeowners were relying on the government instead.",
      "Many homeowners were not aware that flood insurance existed in the first place.",
      "Insurance premiums in Louisiana went up by 70% between 1997-2005, causing many people to cancel their insurance.",
      "Homeowners thought that the likelihood of a flood was too low to justify buying a flood insurance.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under the “Don’t put all your eggs in one basket” analogy, the eggs represent individual investments and the basket represents the overall investment portfolio. Spreading your “eggs” around allows you to:",
    correctAnswer:
      "Minimize the possibility that bad luck for a single investment adversely affects your overall portfolio.",
    propositions: [
      "Minimize the possibility that bad luck for a single investment adversely affects your overall portfolio.",
      "Maximize the possibility that good luck for a single investment positively affects your overall portfolio.",
      "Maximize the return of your overall portfolio.",
      "Increase the uncertainty of your overall portfolio so you can try to generate an extra return.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Risk diversification can be better achieved: (check all that apply)",
    correctAnswer:
      "By including in your portfolio all classes of assets traded in the market, independently of their risks.",
    propositions: [
      "With only low risk assets in your portfolio.",
      "By including in your portfolio all classes of assets traded in the market, independently of their risks.",
      "With mutual funds or unit investment trusts if you hold a small number of assets.",
      "With only stocks in your portfolio.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Short selling, which is defined as the sale of a security that the seller has borrowed, is motivated by the belief that:",
    correctAnswer: "The price of the security will decline.",
    propositions: [
      "The price of the security will rise.",
      "The price of the security will decline.",
      "Short selling is never prompted by speculation.",
      "The price of the security will stay the same.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "The expected return of a portfolio is computed as ___________ and the standard deviation of a portfolio is ___________.",
    correctAnswer:
      "the weighted average of the expected returns of each asset in the portfolio, weighted by the investment in each asset; NOT the weighted average of the standard deviations of each individual asset",
    propositions: [
      "the simple average of the expected returns of each asset in the portfolio; NOT the weighted average of the standard deviations of each individual asset",
      "the weighted average of the expected returns of each asset in the portfolio, weighted by the investment in each asset; NOT the weighted average of the standard deviations of each individual asset",
      "the weighted average of the expected returns of each asset in the portfolio, weighted by the investment in each asset; the weighted average of the standard deviations of each individual asset",
      "the simple average of the expected returns of each asset in the portfolio; the weighted average of the standard deviations of each individual asset",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "The ability to move money from low-return to high-return investments is typically associated with:",
    correctAnswer: "Operational efficiency.",
    propositions: [
      "Technological innovation.",
      "Economies of scale.",
      "Operational efficiency.",
      "Competitive advantage.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is true about an investment in US Treasury bills?",
    correctAnswer: "It is considered risk-free.",
    propositions: [
      "It offers higher returns than stocks.",
      "It is considered risk-free.",
      "It is highly volatile.",
      "It is issued by corporations.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "The primary difference between preferred stock and common stock is:",
    correctAnswer:
      "Preferred stockholders have a higher claim on dividends and assets in the event of liquidation.",
    propositions: [
      "Common stockholders have a higher claim on dividends and assets in the event of liquidation.",
      "Preferred stockholders have a higher claim on dividends and assets in the event of liquidation.",
      "Preferred stockholders have voting rights, whereas common stockholders do not.",
      "Common stockholders receive dividends before preferred stockholders.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is an example of a zero-sum game?",
    correctAnswer: "Poker.",
    propositions: [
      "Poker.",
      "Investment in the stock market.",
      "A manufacturing business.",
      "A charity raffle.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Securities Act of 1933 requires that companies issuing new securities provide investors with:",
    correctAnswer: "A prospectus.",
    propositions: [
      "A financial report.",
      "A prospectus.",
      "A guarantee of returns.",
      "A stock certificate.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is a primary function of an investment bank?",
    correctAnswer: "Underwriting new securities.",
    propositions: [
      "Issuing government bonds.",
      "Providing personal banking services.",
      "Underwriting new securities.",
      "Insuring bank deposits.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What is a common measure of a stock's volatility?",
    correctAnswer: "Beta.",
    propositions: ["Alpha.", "Rho.", "Gamma.", "Beta."],
  },
  {
    question: "The efficient market hypothesis (EMH) suggests that:",
    correctAnswer: "Stock prices fully reflect all available information.",
    propositions: [
      "Investors can consistently achieve higher returns than the market.",
      "Stock prices fully reflect all available information.",
      "Historical price movements can predict future price movements.",
      "Market trends can be identified and exploited for profit.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "In a buy-and-hold strategy, an investor:",
    correctAnswer:
      "Purchases stocks and holds them for a long period regardless of market fluctuations.",
    propositions: [
      "Frequently buys and sells stocks to take advantage of market movements.",
      "Purchases stocks and holds them for a long period regardless of market fluctuations.",
      "Buys only stocks that pay dividends.",
      "Invests only in index funds.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is a feature of a callable bond?",
    correctAnswer: "The issuer can redeem the bond before its maturity date.",
    propositions: [
      "The bondholder can redeem the bond before its maturity date.",
      "The issuer can redeem the bond before its maturity date.",
      "It cannot be converted into stock.",
      "It pays interest only at maturity.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "An option that gives the holder the right to buy a stock at a specified price is called a:",
    correctAnswer: "Call option.",
    propositions: ["Put option.", "Call option.", "Strike option.", "Swap."],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is FALSE of Direct Participation Programs (DPPs)?",
    correctAnswer:
      "They must operate for at least some minimum amount of time.",
    propositions: [
      "They may skip corporate profits tax.",
      "A major example of a DPP is a real estate partnerships.",
      "They must operate for at least some minimum amount of time.",
      "They are for accredited investors only.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "If Sabine is “under water”, what can we say about her situation?",
    correctAnswer:
      "The value of her home is less than the value of her mortgage.",
    propositions: [
      "She has sent her keys to the bank and abandoned her house.",
      "The value of her home is less than the value of her mortgage.",
      "She has no choice but to declare bankruptcy.",
      "She does not have enough money to make payments on her home.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why does the 30 year mortgage rate so closely match the 10 year treasury bond YTM?",
    correctAnswer: "Banks intentionally track the 10 year treasury bond YTM.",
    propositions: [
      "People could choose to finance their home with 10 year treasury bonds instead of with 30 year mortgages.",
      "Banks intentionally track the 10 year treasury bond YTM.",
      "The interest rate of 30 year mortgages and the price of 10 year treasury bonds are set by the same organization.",
      "There are similar psychological causes which influence both the 30 year mortgage rate and the 10 year treasury YTM.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Who pays for private mortgage insurance on a mortgage?",
    correctAnswer: "The homeowner",
    propositions: [
      "The US government",
      "The homeowner",
      "The banks",
      "Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Before the recession in 2007, why were banks giving out mortgages to people who could not afford them?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Banks would resell to mortgages to CMOs, and thus they were not incentivized to make sure their mortgages were unlikely to default.",
    propositions: [
      "Banks would resell to mortgages to CMOs, and thus they were not incentivized to make sure their mortgages were unlikely to default.",
      "CMOs were incentivized to buy mortgages which were likely to default, since these would only affect their lowest tranche.",
      "Many people faked documents in order to get a mortgage, known as a 'liar loan'.",
      "Banks had no way to verify whether people would be able to pay.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Select TWO key causes of the housing bubble which crashed in 2007:",
    correctAnswer: [
      "Fraudulent mortgage lending",
      "Over-optimistic mortgage lending",
    ],
    propositions: [
      "Fraudulent mortgage lending",
      "Over-optimistic mortgage lending",
      "Hyper-inflation",
      "Corruption within the government",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "During the housing bubble of 2007, which of the following tended to fluctuate with home price index?",
    correctAnswer:
      "The percentage of new homeowners who think that investing in real estate is a good long term investment.",
    propositions: [
      "The percentage of new homeowners who regretted their decision.",
      "The percentage of new homeowners who think that investing in real estate is a good long term investment.",
      "The percentage of new homeowners who have been evicted from their home.",
      "The percentage of new homeowners who think investing in real estate is a bad long term investment.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What in 2005 indicated the housing market might be a bubble?",
    correctAnswer:
      "The expected 10 year home price appreciation dropped below the 30 year mortgage rate.",
    propositions: [
      "The expected 10 year home price appreciation dropped below the 30 year mortgage rate.",
      "Media was discussing a home-buying mania in the American public.",
      "Media was discussing how people were no longer purchasing houses.",
      "Time magazine predicted that the housing market was a bubble.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Why might companies like the idea of regulation?",
    correctAnswer:
      "It allows them to compete on a level at which they do not have to use (potentially unethical or unfair) special tricks to avoid letting their competitors gain a competitive advantage.",
    propositions: [
      "It helps them ensure they are representing the interests of their customers.",
      "Regulation could be used to give them a legal monopoly over a particular sector.",
      "Companies have enough money to bribe government officials to create regulation that favors them.",
      "It allows them to compete on a level at which they do not have to use (potentially unethical or unfair) special tricks to avoid letting their competitors gain a competitive advantage.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What is tunneling?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Any trick that somebody in the company uses to steal money from the company.",
    propositions: [
      "When management of a company transfers cash from a corporate account to a personal account.",
      "When a member of the board of directors fires a high ranking employee so that a family member can take their place.",
      "When a small group of majority shareholders in a company allow the company to be bought out for a very low price by another company in which the small group are also majority shareholders.",
      "Any trick that somebody in the company uses to steal money from the company.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Ideally, who must the board of directors be loyal to?",
    correctAnswer: "The shareholders",
    propositions: [
      "The government",
      "The shareholders",
      "The general public",
      "The CEO",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What is a fixed commission?",
    correctAnswer:
      "A fixed rate charged by all brokerages to buy or sell shares on the stock market.",
    propositions: [
      "The opposite of dividends, i.e. fixed per-share prices charged by companies to shareholders.",
      "The rate charged in order to join a trade groups.",
      "Fixed taxes imposed on brokerages if they wished to operate in the stock market.",
      "A fixed rate charged by all brokerages to buy or sell shares on the stock market.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following describes the contrast of federal vs state regulation in the US?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Securities are primarily regulated by federal government but corporate regulation is primarily by the state governments.",
    propositions: [
      "Securities regulation and corporate regulation are both primarily controlled by the state governments.",
      "Securities regulation and corporate regulation are both primarily controlled by the federal government.",
      "Securities are primarily regulated by federal government but corporate regulation is primarily by the state governments.",
      "Securities are primarily regulated by state governments but corporate regulation is primarily by the federal government.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) NOT responsible for doing?",
    correctAnswer:
      "To authorize companies to be traded publicly on the stock market.",
    propositions: [
      "To authorize companies to be traded publicly on the stock market.",
      "To provide reliable and timely information on the performance of securities.",
      "To force organizations to maintain financial transparency.",
      "To manage the EDGAR database.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What happened when Goodbody and Company failed?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Because Goodbody and Company held the shares for their clients, people lost most or all of their stocks.",
    propositions: [
      "People began to distrust brokerages and pulled their money out of stocks.",
      "None of the retail investors lost any money.",
      "Goodbody and Company had to mail everybody their stocks before they failed.",
      "Because Goodbody and Company held the shares for their clients, people lost most or all of their stocks.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following describes the Bank for International Settlements (BIS)?",
    correctAnswer:
      "A bank for central banks which provides an intermediary for the central banks to deal with each other.",
    propositions: [
      "A bank for citizens of any country which allows them to deal in other currencies.",
      "A former financial institution which was replaced by the G20.",
      "The English name for the national bank of Switzerland, which strategically fosters relationships between banks internationally.",
      "A bank for central banks which provides an intermediary for the central banks to deal with each other.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the effect of traders storing grain to wait for higher prices?",
    correctAnswer: "It is essential in preventing grain shortages.",
    propositions: [
      "It is essential in preventing grain shortages.",
      "Most shortages could have been prevented if traders had not speculated on grain prices.",
      "Most grain ends up getting moldy in storage.",
      "Traders are able to monopolize the market.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "In commodities trading, what is the role of forwards and futures?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Warehouses buy from the farmer in forwards, and then hedge on futures.",
    propositions: [
      "Farmers and warehouses sell exclusively in futures contracts.",
      "Warehouses sell exclusively in forwards contracts.",
      "Warehouses buy from the farmer in forwards, and then hedge on futures.",
      "There is no difference between forwards and futures in commodities trading.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the interest rate derivatives market, what is the general relationship between market value and notional value?",
    correctAnswer: "Notional value is greater than market value.",
    propositions: [
      "Market value is greater than notional value.",
      "Notional value is greater than market value.",
      "Market value and notional value are always equal.",
      "Market value is equal to notional value.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is an example of a common hedging strategy in corporate finance?",
    correctAnswer: "Setting the beta of a portfolio to 0.",
    propositions: [
      "Setting the beta of a portfolio to 1.",
      "Setting the beta of a portfolio to 0.",
      "Setting the beta of a portfolio to -1.",
      "Setting the beta of a portfolio to a random value.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is an example of a corporate governance principle?",
    correctAnswer: "Fairness",
    propositions: [
      "Profit maximization",
      "Risk management",
      "Shareholder wealth maximization",
      "Fairness",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What does the term 'democratization of finance' mean?",
    correctAnswer:
      "It should benefit real people; everyone, not just the rich.",
    propositions: [
      "It should benefit the youngest people; not the old.",
      "It should benefit the oldest people; not the young.",
      "It should benefit rich people; not the poor.",
      "It should benefit real people; everyone, not just the rich.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What is 'odious' debt?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Illegitimate debt raised by government, used for ill purposes against the will of the people.",
    propositions: [
      "Standard debt raised by corporations, to create new products.",
      "Illegitimate debt raised by corporations.",
      "Illegitimate debt raised by government, used for ill purposes against the will of the people.",
      "Standard debt raised by government.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Malthus contended that:",
    correctAnswer:
      "Human population can grow faster than humans can produce commensurate amounts of food.",
    propositions: [
      "Poverty causes resource depletion rather than the reverse.",
      "All of the above.",
      "By providing additional workers human population growth enhanced economic development.",
      "Human population can grow faster than humans can produce commensurate amounts of food.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Malthus contended that population, when unchecked, increased in a ______ ratio; and subsistence for man in an _______ ratio.",
    correctAnswer: "Geometrical; arithmetical",
    propositions: [
      "Linear; geometrical",
      "Geometrical; arithmetical",
      "Arithmetical; linear",
      "Arithmetical; geometrical",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What are some reasons that inequality exists? (check all that apply)",
    correctAnswer:
      "Unmanaged risks, Political power, Failure to democratize finance.",
    propositions: [
      "Unmanaged risks",
      "Political power",
      "Failure to democratize finance.",
      "None of the above.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why was the Yale portfolio primarily in bonds and other 'safe' investments?",
    correctAnswer: "Yale was following the best practice advice of Joe McNay",
    propositions: [
      "Yale was following the best practice advice of Joe McNay",
      "Yale did not want the strong variation that are common in investment",
      "Yale had too much money for other investments",
      "Yale did not have a portfolio manager",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is NOT an example of moral hazard?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Not farming efficiently because farming insurance will cover the cost of a bad crop.",
    propositions: [
      "Lying about farming yields to collect insurance money.",
      "Neglecting to replace smoke detector batteries when insured against fire.",
      "Knowingly building a house in an area susceptible to floods",
      "Not farming efficiently because farming insurance will cover the cost of a bad crop.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "All rational investors, seeking to manage risk by optimally diversifying across a common set of different assets:",
    correctAnswer:
      "Ultimately earn the same return if they share the same level of risk-aversion.",
    propositions: [
      "Only focus on the mean of the overall portfolio.",
      "Can ultimately hold different, fully diversified portfolios.",
      "Are concerned about by the performance of the riskier assets once they have created the diversifying portfolio.",
      "Ultimately earn the same return if they share the same level of risk-aversion.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "If you want to protect the risk consisting in the fluctuations of the value of your home, you would ideally:",
    correctAnswer: "Want to short the market for homes in your city.",
    propositions: [
      "Want to be long (buyer) in the market for homes in your city.",
      "Want to stay market-neutral (neither long nor short) in the market for homes in your city.",
      "Avoid investing in the housing market in your city.",
      "Want to short the market for homes in your city.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "Regarding the Efficient Market Hypothesis:",
    correctAnswer:
      "It states that asset prices fully reflect all available information.",
    propositions: [
      "It states that asset prices fully reflect all available information.",
      "It implies that no investor can consistently achieve higher returns than the overall market.",
      "It suggests that market anomalies are common and persistent.",
      "It assumes that all investors are rational and have access to the same information.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Federal Funds Futures Market?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Futures contracts created by an exchange board which are settled at the end of each month for 100 minus the federal funds rate averaged over the month.",
    propositions: [
      "Futures contracts created by the government which are settled at the end of each year for 100 minus the federal funds rate averaged over the month.",
      "Futures contracts created by an exchange board which are settled at the end of each month for 100 minus the federal funds rate averaged over the month.",
      "Futures contracts created by an exchange board which are settled at the end of each year for 100 minus the federal funds rate averaged over the month.",
      "Futures contracts created by the government which are settled at the end of each month for 100 minus the federal funds rate averaged over the month.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What are the two types of options?",
    correctAnswer:
      "A 'call' option is the right to buy and a 'put' option is the right to sell.",
    propositions: [
      "A 'call' option is the right to buy and a 'put' option is the right to sell.",
      "A 'put' option is the right to buy and a 'call' option is the right to sell.",
      "A 'get' option is the right to buy and a 'push' option is the right to sell.",
      "A 'push' option is the right to buy and a 'get' option is the right to sell.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why do some stock options have an exercise price which is more than the cost of the stock?",
    correctAnswer:
      "For 'call' options, this provides the option to buy at this price if the stock goes up before the exercise date.",
    propositions: [
      "New investors often mistake 'put' and 'call' options, leading to an easy profit for the dealer.",
      "For 'call' options, this provides the option to buy at this price if the stock goes up before the exercise date.",
      "These options are 'put' options, giving you the option to sell at a higher price.",
      "The stock options sell for negative prices, because the investor will lose money if the stock price does not fluctuate.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is NOT a behavioral reason why people buy options?",
    correctAnswer:
      "Portfolio managers will usually buy options for clients without them knowing so that if the stock price goes down, the manager will come across as thinking ahead and watching out for their clients.",
    propositions: [
      "Portfolio managers will usually buy options for clients without them knowing so that if the stock price goes down, the manager will come across as thinking ahead and watching out for their clients.",
      "People will feel better about themselves if their stocks go down if they have purchased a put option on them, regardless of whether or not they gained or lost overall.",
      "They are fooled by salespeople.",
      "People will pay attention to specific aspects of their portfolio more so than others, so they will buy options when they hear about volatility in the market to protect certain components of their portfolio.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Are mortgages in the US similar to options from the perspective of the homeowner?",
    correctAnswer: "No in recourse states, yes in non-recourse states.",
    propositions: [
      "No, because defaulting does not eliminate liability.",
      "Yes, because people always have the option to default.",
      "Yes, because they can be sold by banks to Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac.",
      "No in recourse states, yes in non-recourse states.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What is the put-call parity relationship?",
    correctAnswer:
      "A relationship between the put price, the call price, and the stock price for European-style stock options.",
    propositions: [
      "A relationship between the put price, the call price, and the stock price for European-style stock options.",
      "A method of arbitrage for options exchanges.",
      "Another name for the Black-Scholes model.",
      "A mathematical formula specifying that the put price of an option minus the call price of an option equals the price of the stock.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What is a stop-loss order?",
    correctAnswer:
      "An instruction to your broker indicating that they should sell your shares once it drops below some price.",
    propositions: [
      "An instruction to your broker indicating that they should sell your shares once it drops below some price.",
      "A type of stock that will protect you against losing too much money on the stock market.",
      "A type of order that will instruct your broker to buy more shares if the price rises above a certain threshold.",
      "An order that your broker must follow to avoid paying capital gains taxes on certain transactions.",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of passive management?",
    correctAnswer: "It requires frequent buying and selling of stocks.",
    propositions: [
      "It requires frequent buying and selling of stocks.",
      "It involves lower fees than active management.",
      "It tends to outperform actively managed funds over the long term.",
      "It is based on the efficient market hypothesis, which states that asset prices fully reflect all available information.",
    ],
  },
];
